why do the little disembodied brains we
grow in jars have eyes and do they work
a lot of people asked that and I wanted
to address that specifically the group
that researched them were able to
spontaneously develop the eye structures
in the disembodied brain organoids and
they did actually function as eyes they
received white information and processed
it similar to what we might think of as
a thought about the white I wanted to
show you guys this picture so you can
see just how tiny these little guys
actually are the reason they have eyes
is because they are just little teeny
tiny developing brains made of stem
cells they develop eyes the same way a
human would during development it starts
out with these little optic cups and
they develop to what is eventually the
retina if everything goes right and yes
eyes are made of neural progenitor
tissue I also wanted to mention the
brain waves so the little brain
organoids were found after a certain
number of months of development to have
similar brain waves to delta waves which
are the w W found in deep sleep and
found in pre-term babies this does have
really interesting consequences because
it either means that babies are not as
great as we thought or the brain
organoids are more complex than we
thought neither one of those is
something that I really want to consider
for too long it's like staring into the
void here's a paper on the brain waves
if you want to read it you can find it
on Google scholar just type in that
topic let me know if you want to learn
more